If you had to guess what menu sells more,
menu number one or menu number two?
Researchers actually looked at this
and figured out what the answer was.
So they did this test with a bunch of jam stands
where they had one stand that had 24 types of jam
and another stand that had only six.
And they had people walk up to it.
What was interesting is that one of these jam stands
converted significantly higher than the other.
And you might think, oh, the more selection people have,
the more likely they are to buy the perfect thing for them.
But in reality, what ended up happening
is that people were 10 times more likely to buy
when they had fewer selections
because the decision was easier.
We actually implemented this kind of perspective
with a portfolio company right as we invested.
And they had a kind of like,
choose your own adventure type thing.
Like whatever you can think of, we'll sell it to you.
And so what we looked at when we pulled all the data
was we figured out that there are actually
two customer avatars they had
and they bought two very different sets of things.
And so we said, okay, what is 80% of the time
this person buy and what is 80% of the time this person buy?
And then we completely consolidated to choice A
and choice B for customer A and customer B.
What happened is we were able to actually sell more people
at higher prices, templatize the solution on the back
and sort of expand margin
because we were able to do the same thing
for more times for more people
and it would on ramp sales people faster
because they didn't have to learn the whole menu.
They only had to learn two things
and then customers transacted faster
and we cut the sales time in half.
If you believe in free markets
is the best way to incentivize people
and you believe in pro-capitalism,
you'll like my money making stuff,
you can fall for more of it.